Linh Vuu

Current Address:

111A Baker Tower Ithaca, NY 14853 (347) 322-2331 • lav59@cornell.edu https://www.linkedin.com/in/linh-vuu-807986a3

Permanent Address:

175 Zoe Street, Apt. #1A Staten Island, NY 10305

OBJECTIVE

Further expand quantitative and qualitative analytical skills by developing knowledge and experience to build my career in the financial industry. To learn about risk tolerance strategies, methods of market valuation & capitalization, and financial policy initiatives.

EDUCATION

CORNELL UNIVERSITY, CHARLES H. DYSON SCHOOL OF APPLIED ECONOMICS & MANAGEMENT Bachelor of Science in Applied Economics and Management, May 2018; GPA: 3.53

Concentrations: Finance • Environmental, Energy, and Resource Economics

RELATED EXPERIENCE

STANDARD CHARTERED BANK

Summer 2017

Corporate & Institutional Banking Intern

- Work with Global Relationship Managers on the Industrials, Services, & Transportation coverage team.
- Develop prospective client relationships aligned with SCB footprint in Asia, Middle East, & Africa.
- Participate in deal execution & origination task, e.g. pitch books, call reports, due diligence, credit review.
- Coordinate with Transaction Banking & Financial Markets product groups to provide strategic advisory.

OFFICE OF NYC COMPTROLLER

Summer 2016

Asset Management Intern

- Engage in investment control functions to tabulate transaction history for Alternative Investments group.
- Verify partnership contracts and investment positions settled accurately and timely with custody bank.
- Discuss portfolio strategies that optimize sourcing & deal flow to protect pensions of beneficiaries.
- Direct allocations to investment advisors following rigorous procurement and compliance procedures.

NEW YORK CITY COUNCIL

Summer 2013

Budget & Legislative Intern

- Consolidate accounts for internal audit; analyze budget to allocate resources for municipal projects.
- Research data on socioeconomic impact of local construction; developed environmental policy report.
- Utilize cost-benefit analysis to assess trade-offs, seek alternative funding, and draft budget legislation.

ACTIVITIES

DYSON LEADERSHIP FELLOWS PROGRAM

January 2015 - Current

- Develop foundation for ethical leadership through analytical research, outreach, skill-building workshops.
- Streamline initiatives to encourage alumni engagement and restructure program management.
- Cultivate brand awareness through social media platforms to attract new recruits and sponsorship leads.
- Manage conference scheduling; propose seminars to develop students' skills, i.e. Innovation Dialogue.

APEX INVESTMENT CLUB

October 2014 - Current

- Develop valuation models, employ trading strategies, maximize portfolio value, and hedge against risk.
- Present weekly stock pitches and market updates for: financial institutions group and energy group.

CALS HONORS RESEARCH THESIS PROGRAM

January 2015 - Current

- Critically analyze China's environmental policies; study its transition to "new normal" economic growth.
- Extensively research the impact of circular economy on the amelioration of environmental externalities.

PRESIDENT'S SUSTAINABLE CAMPUS COMMITTEE

April 2015 - Current

- Serve as campus ambassador for Energy Focus team to promote student-led energy saving initiatives.
- Assess conservation measures; act in advisory capacity to integrate sustainability into university functions.

HONORS

Gates Millennium Scholar, NYS Academic Scholarship, Barclays Externship, JP Morgan Winning Women Program, PMA Career Pathways Program, Harvard Project for Asian & International Relations Conference

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Software: Bloomberg Professional, Microsoft Office Suite, MiniTab, HTML/CSS/PHP/JavaScript Language: Limited working proficiency in Spanish & Vietnamese. Elementary proficiency in Cantonese.